<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<prospectus updated="2020-04-24T10:00:00">
    <institute color="#5da733" url="ias">
        <info>
            <name lang="en">Institute of the Applied Science</name>
            <name lang="mt">Institute of the Applied Science</name>

            <description lang="en">Applied Science relates to the application of scientific knowledge to practical challenges and jobs. At the Institute of Applied Sciences, learners are prepared for technological careers within the health, pharmaceutical, environmental, food and beverage, or general engineering sectors. Students learn to appreciate how the fundamental principles of science relate to the technological operations of the workplace, while developing the skills to work in laboratories, hospitals, farms, and with environmental technologies and methodologies, as well as to apply basic scientific principles in industrial settings. Successful and unsuccessful people do not vary greatly in their abilities. The Institute building at the main campus includes eleven fully-equipped laboratories for training and research in several scientific and technological fields. At the CAAAS Qormi Campus, learners make use of facilities required for studies in a more practical and hands-on approach.</description>
            <description lang="mt">Applied Science relates to the application of scientific knowledge to practical challenges and jobs. At the Institute of Applied Sciences, learners are prepared for technological careers within the health, pharmaceutical, environmental, food and beverage, or general engineering sectors. Students learn to appreciate how the fundamental principles of science relate to the technological operations of the workplace, while developing the skills to work in laboratories, hospitals, farms, and with environmental technologies and methodologies, as well as to apply basic scientific principles in industrial settings. Successful and unsuccessful people do not vary greatly in their abilities. The Institute building at the main campus includes eleven fully-equipped laboratories for training and research in several scientific and technological fields. At the CAAAS Qormi Campus, learners make use of facilities required for studies in a more practical and hands-on approach.</description>
        </info>

        <testimonials>
            <testimonial name="Iman Bussitil" qualification="Scientific Officer">I am now responsible for coordinating the International Bottom Trawl Survey in the Mediterranean.</testimonial>
            <testimonial name="Ina Ghergel" qualification="Scientific Officer">MCAST was an important step in my career, as it led me to this career, to develop myself and to implement the knowledge I learned.</testimonial>
        </testimonials>

        <courses>
            <course name="Introductory Certificate in Applied Science" code="AS1-01-19" mqf="1" length="1 year" mode="full-time">
                <description lang="en">This course of studies aims to provide the learner with the basic knowledge of science and technology and how these apply to everyday life. The study units deal with the different disciplines of science hence giving the learner an overview of all the main scientific concepts necessary as a basis for further vocational studies within the science sector.</description>
                <description lang="mt">Dan il-programm ta’ studji għandu l-għan li jipprovdi lill-istudent l-għarfien bażiku tax-xjenza u t-teknoloġija u kif dawn japplikaw għall-ħajja ta’ kuljum. L-unitajiet ta’ studju jindirizzaw id-dixxiplini differenti tax-xjenza u għaldaqstant jagħtu lill-istudent ħarsa ġenerali lejn il-kunċetti xjentifiċi ewlenin kollha meħtieġa bħala bażi għal studji vokazzjonali ulterjuri fis-settur tax- xjenza.</description>

                <requirements>
                    <requirement type="compulsory">Finished Compulsory Education</requirement>
                    <requirement type="optional">Initial Assessment Tests (as may be applicable)</requirement>
                </requirements>

                <opportunities>
                    <opportunity></opportunity>
                </opportunities>
            </course>
        </courses>
    </institute>
    
    <institute color="#ca2f88" url="ica">
        <info>
            <name lang="en">Institute for the Creative Arts</name>
            <name lang="mt">Istitut tal-Arti Kreattiva</name>

            <description lang="en">Formerly known as the Institute of Art and Design, this institute was established in 2001, merging the expertise of the Art and Design Centre and Salvatore Dimech School for Craftsmen. In 2014, the name was changed to Institute for the Creative Arts to reflect its growing portfolio of courses offered, ranging from art and design to graphic design and interactive media, creative media production, photography and journalism, and recently, fashion design and performing arts as well as cultural heritage skills. The Institute works closely with the industry
to provide students with realistic assignment briefs and experiences. The creative arts play a crucial role in communicating visions and ideas which words alone cannot fully express. They may also be perceived as means to educate, to provide a cultural identity and act as agents of change.</description>
            <description lang="mt">Dan l-Istitut, li ġie stabbilit fl-2001, qabel kien magħruf bħala l-Istitut tal-Arti u d-Disinn u jgħaqqad flimkien il-kompetenza taċ-Ċentru tal-Arti u d-Disinn, u l-Iskola Salvatore Dimech għal Persuni tas-Sengħa. Fl-2014, l-isem inbidel għall-Istitut għall-Arti Kreattiva, biex jirrifletti l-portafoll dejjem jikber ta’ korsijiet offruti, li jvarjaw mill-arti u d-disinn, għaddisinn grafiku u l-midja interattiva, il-produzzjoni tal-midja kreattiva, il-fotografija u l-ġurnaliżmu, id-disinn tal-moda u l-arti tal-ispettaklu, kif ukoll il-ħiliet tal-patrimonju kulturali. L-Istitut jaħdem mill-qrib mal-industrija biex jipprovdi lill-istudenti tagħrif u esperjenzi ta’ xogħol realistiċi. L-arti kreattiva għandha rwol kruċjali fil-komunikazzjoni ta’ viżjonijiet u ideat li ma jistgħux jiġu espressi bil-kliem biss. Tista’ tiġi meqjusa wkoll bħala mezz ta’ edukazzjoni, li tipprovdi identità kulturali u taġixxi bħala aġent tal-bidla.</description>
        </info>

        <testimonials>
            <testimonial name="Leander Schembri" qualification="Graphic Designer">Having my portfolio in people’s fridges gives me great pride!</testimonial>
            <testimonial name="Johann Caruana" qualification="Video Content Executive">...have laid the foundation to my successful career.</testimonial>
        </testimonials>

        <courses>
            <course name="Introductory Certificate in Art and Design" code="AD1-01-19" mqf="1" length="1 year" mode="full-time">
                <description lang="en">This programme of studies provides learners, who completed their compulsory education and are in possession of their Secondary School Certificate and Profile (SSC&amp;P), with an opportunity to follow an introductory course in the field of art and design. The programme of studies focuses on basic art and design principles, with an emphasis on vocational practice. This enables learners to understand better the vocation they intend to follow and prepare them for further training in the field. Key skills subjects help the learners improve their competences within basic areas such as language, numeracy, information technology, science and individual and social responsibility.</description>
                <description lang="mt">Dan il-programm ta’ studji jipprovdi lill-istudenti, li jkunu spiċċaw l-edukazzjoni obbligatorja tagħhom u li għandhom iċ-Ċertifikat u l-Profil tal-Iskola Sekondarja (SSC&amp;P) tagħhom, l-opportunità li jsegwu kors introduttorju fil-qasam tal-arti u d-disinn. Il-programm ta’ studji jiffoka fuq il-prinċipji bażiċi tal-arti u d-disinn, b’enfasi fuq il-prattika vokazzjonali. Dan jippermetti lill-istudenti jifhmu aħjar il-vokazzjoni li biħsiebhom isegwu u jħejjihom għal aktar taħriġ fil-qasam. Suġġetti ta’ ħiliet ewlenin jgħinu lill-istudenti jtejbu l-kompetenzi tagħhom f’oqsma bażiċi bħal-lingwa, in-numeriżmu, it-teknoloġija tal-informazzjoni, ix-xjenza u r-responsabbiltà individwali u soċjali.</description>

                <requirements>
                    <requirement type="compulsory">Finished Compulsory Education</requirement>
                    <requirement type="optional">Initial Assessment Tests (as may be applicable)</requirement>
                </requirements>

                <opportunities>
                    <opportunity></opportunity>
                </opportunities>
            </course>

            <course name="Bachelor of Arts (Honours) in Game Art and Visual Design" code="AD6-03-19" mqf="6" length="3 years" mode="full-time">
                <description lang="en">This degree programme has been developed in response to the increased demand for trained artists and designers who are able to produce rich, interactive experiences by developing conceptual visual graphics for digital games. Learners further their skills in drawing and illustration - the basis for the eventual development of game art. They acquire grounding in essential art and design principles, as well as computer-generated design, and concurrently receive a basic knowledge of related theory, analysis and practice. This includes game design, psychology of play, user interface (UI), narrative study, digital imaging, 3D-modelling and animation.</description>
                <description lang="mt">Dan il-programm fil-livell tal-baċellerat ġie żviluppat bi tweġiba għad-domanda dejjem tiżdied għal artisti u disinjaturi mħarrġa li jistgħu jipproduċu esperjenzi rikki u interattivi billi jiżviluppaw grafiċi viżivi kunċettwali għal-logħob diġitali. L-istudenti jkomplu jiżviluppaw il-ħiliet tagħhom fit-tpinġija u l-illustrazzjoni – il-bażi għall-iżvilupp eventwali tal-arti tal-logħob. Huma għandhom jiksbu bażi tajba fil-prinċipji essenzjali tal-arti u d-disinn, kif ukoll fid-disinn iġġenerat mill-kompjuter, u fl-istess ħin jirċievu għarfien bażiku ta’ teorija, analiżi u prattika relatati. Dan jinkludi d-disinn tal-logħob, il-psikoloġija tal-logħob, l-interfaċċa tal-utent (UI), l-istudju tan-narrattiva, l-immaġni diġitali, l-immudellar tridimensjonali u l-animazzjoni.</description>

                <requirements>
                    <requirement type="compulsory">MCAST Advanced Diploma in Art and Design</requirement>
                    <requirement type="compulsory">MCAST Advanced Diploma in Graphic Design and Interactive Media</requirement>
                    <requirement type="compulsory">2 A-Level passes and 2 I-Level passes<br />Compulsory A-Level: Art, or Art and Design, or equivalent</requirement>
                    <requirement type="optional">Applicants may be asked to sit for an interview and/or present their Portfolio</requirement>
                </requirements>

                <opportunities>
                    <opportunity>Digital visual artist</opportunity>
                    <opportunity>Storyboard artist</opportunity>
                    <opportunity>Texture artist</opportunity>
                    <opportunity>Concept artist</opportunity>
                    <opportunity>3D Artist</opportunity>
                    <opportunity>3D Rigger</opportunity>
                    <opportunity>3D Modeller</opportunity>
                </opportunities>
            </course>
        </courses>
    </institute>
</prospectus>
